<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Chia Yong Kang</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Chia Yong Kang</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alpenglow: A Look at Solana&#39;s Landmark Upgrade for Near-Instant Finality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/alpenglow-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/alpenglow-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/alpenglow-anza.png&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;The Matterhorn at sunrise, a visual representation of &amp;lsquo;alpenglow&amp;rsquo;.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Alpenglow&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Matterhorn at sunrise, a visual representation of &amp;lsquo;alpenglow&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article summarizes Alpenglow, Solana&amp;rsquo;s most significant upgrade, designed to slash transaction finality time. Alpenglow replaces legacy components like Tower BFT and Proof of History (PoH) to achieve block finality up to 100 times faster, targeting a median time of just 150 milliseconds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;video width=&#34;100%&#34; controls&gt;&#xA;  &lt;source src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/videos/alpen-sim.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Your browser does not support the video tag.&#xA;&lt;/video&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;high-level-changes&#34;&gt;High-Level Changes&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The diagram below shows the core architectural shift from Solana&amp;rsquo;s legacy components to the new Alpenglow protocol.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arbitrage Trading Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/arbitrage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/arbitrage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the textbook basics - the definition. What is arbitrage afterall? Well, the dictionary will give you this definition:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the simultaneous buying and selling of securities, currency, or commodities in different markets or in derivative forms in order to take advantage of differing prices for the same asset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d say this is a fairly good definition for arbitrage in the traditional sense, but in the modern sense&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure this is true. Most advanced arbitrage trading doesn&amp;rsquo;t hedge the other side of the trade simultaneously at all. If you are in and out of the position in a couple seconds, then why would you even care about being hedged? Especially if you know that the side you are trading is the one doing all the moving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There are just too many AI Frameworks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/ai-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/ai-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;there-are-just-too-many-ai-frameworks&#34;&gt;There are just too many AI Frameworks&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://extremelysunnyyk.medium.com/&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve all been here before. A new technology emerges, frameworks proliferate to make it accessible, and eventually, we hit the ceiling of complexity and fragmentation. The AI ecosystem today feels eerily similar to the early days of JavaScript frameworks or the explosion of NoSQL databases — too many choices, too little consolidation, and a growing sense that we might be making things harder, not easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unofficial Guide to Rust Optimization Techniques</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/rust-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/rust-optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;unofficial-guide-to-rust-optimization-techniques&#34;&gt;Unofficial Guide to Rust Optimization Techniques&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://extremelysunnyyk.medium.com/&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rust&amp;rsquo;s unique ownership model and zero-cost abstractions make it an exceptional language for building high-performance systems. However, writing fast Rust code requires understanding both the language&amp;rsquo;s performance characteristics and the underlying hardware. This guide covers advanced optimization techniques that can help you squeeze every bit of performance out of your Rust applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-rusts-performance-model&#34;&gt;Understanding Rust&amp;rsquo;s Performance Model&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;zero-cost-abstractions&#34;&gt;Zero-Cost Abstractions&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rust&amp;rsquo;s promise of zero-cost abstractions means that high-level constructs don&amp;rsquo;t impose runtime overhead. However, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t automatically make your code fast - it just means the abstractions won&amp;rsquo;t slow you down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Drift: Architecting a High-Performance Orderbook on Solana</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/drift-orderbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/drift-orderbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;inside-drift-architecting-a-high-performance-orderbook-on-solana&#34;&gt;Inside Drift: Architecting a High-Performance Orderbook on Solana&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://extremelysunnyyk.medium.com/inside-drift-architecting-a-high-performance-orderbook-on-solana-612a98b8ac17&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Drift Protocol is Solana&amp;rsquo;s largest open-source perpetual futures DEX, enabling low-slippage, high-leverage trading with cross-margining. It&amp;rsquo;s crucial for DeFi, handling over $20B in volume since 2021, per CoinGecko.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;architecture-of-drift&#34;&gt;Architecture of Drift&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The architecture of Drift Protocol is built upon the high-performance capabilities of the Solana blockchain, which are essential for supporting a derivatives exchange with features like high leverage and complex order types. Solana&amp;rsquo;s inherent speed and low transaction costs directly contribute to a smoother and more cost-effective trading experience for users on the Drift platform.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Engineer&#39;s Guide to Building and Validating Quantitative Trading Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/quant-trading-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/quant-trading-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-engineers-guide-to-building-and-validating-quantitative-trading-strategies&#34;&gt;An Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Building and Validating Quantitative Trading Strategies&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://extremelysunnyyk.medium.com/&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From data collection to statistical validation — a rigorous framework for developing profitable trading algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quantitative trading has evolved from a niche discipline practiced by a few Wall Street firms to a democratized field accessible to individual developers. However, the gap between a profitable backtest and a live trading system remains vast. This guide provides a systematic approach to building, validating, and deploying quantitative trading strategies that can survive the transition from theory to practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
